Guide to the Harold F. Gosnell Papers 1886-1997
University of Chicago Library
- Series VII: Research Files
  - Subseries 3: Voting
    - Compulsory voting, America, circa 1930s (Box 92, Folder 6-7)
    - Compulsory voting, Australia, circa 1930s (Box 92, Folder 8)
    - Disenfranchisement, 1930s (Box 92, Folder 9-11)
    - Economic motivations, circa 1924-1940 (Box 93, Folder 1)
    - Election reform, 1929 (Box 93, Folder 2)
    - Electoral behavior, 1930s-1950s (Box 93, Folder 3-6)
    - European elections project, undated (Box 93, Folder 7)
    - Exit polling, 1980-1984 (Box 93, Folder 8)
    - Foreign-born voters, circa 1930 (Box 93, Folder 9)
    - Independent voters, 1930s (Box 93, Folder 10-11)
    - "A New View of Compulsory Voting," undated (Box 93, Folder 12)
    - Nominations and petitions, circa 1930s (Box 93, Folder 12)
    - Participation and nonvoting, circa 1920s-1930s, undated (Box 93, Folder 14-16)
    - Participation, primaries, 1930 (Box 94, Folder 1-6)
    - Party affiliation, nineteenth century (Box 94, Folder 7)
    - Politics and the Depression, 1930s (Box 94, Folder 8)
    - Pressure groups and propaganda, 1932-1934 (Box 94, Folder 9)
    - "Property Qualifications in Voting," undated (Box 94, Folder 10)
    - Proportional representation, 1923-1931 (Box 95, Folder 1-4)
    - Race, undated (Box 95, Folder 5)
    - Radio influence, 1930s-1940s (Box 95, Folder 6-7)
    - Recalls, circa 1930s (Box 95, Folder 8)
    - Referenda, 1936 (Box 96, Folder 1)
    - Suffrage and citizenship, undated (Box 96, Folder 2)
    - Theories of voting, 1956, undated (Box 96, Folder 3)
    - Voter turn-out, 1927-1928 (Box 96, Folder 4)
  - Subseries 4: Public Opinion
    - Agriculture and commerce, circa 1950s (Box 96, Folder 5-6)
    - Behavioural analysis, circa 1950s (Box 96, Folder 7)
    - Careers and education, 1950s-1960s (Box 96, Folder 8-11)
    - "Common Sense" magazine, 1935 (Box 96, Folder 12)
    - Elections, 1880, 1924 (Box 96, Folder 13-14)
    - Elections, 1932 (Box 97, Folder 1-8)
    - Elections, 1932 (Box 98, Folder 1-3)
    - Employment and unemployment, 1950s (Box 98, Folder 4)
    - Immigration and American culture, circa 1967 (Box 98, Folder 5)
    - Interviews and interviewing technique, undated (Box 98, Folder 6)
    - "Influence of Public Opinion on Public Policy," undated (Box 98, Folder 7)
    - "Leadership Study," 1928 (Box 98, Folder 8-9)
    - Measuring political success, 1939 (Box 98, Folder 10)
    - Multiple factor analysis, circa 1930s (Box 98, Folder 11)
    - Policymaking, 1940s (Box 98, Folder 12)
    - Political science and public opinion, 1935 (Box 98, Folder 13)
    - Political stratification, undated (Box 99, Folder 1)
    - Polling methods, undated (Box 99, Folder 2-5)
    - "Processes Underlying Exposure to Advertising," 1968 (Box 99, Folder 6)
    - Processing data, undated (Box 99, Folder 7-11)
    - Proportional representation, circa 1910s (Box 100, Folder 1)
    - "Public Opinion News Service," 1961 (Box 100, Folder 2)
    - "Public Opinion Regarding the Status of Color Television," 1950 (Box 100, Folder 3)
    - "Public Opinion," undated (Box 100, Folder 4-5)
    - Public relations, circa 1960s (Box 100, Folder 6)
    - Race and the social sciences, circa 1920s (Box 100, Folder 7)
    - Radio and television, undated (Box 100, Folder 8)
    - Sample surveys, undated (Box 100, Folder 9-10)
    - Social psychology, circa 1950 (Box 100, Folder 11)
    - Space program, 1977 (Box 100, Folder 12)
    - Statistical research theories, 1960s (Box 100, Folder 13)
    - Statistical technique, 1968 (Box 100, Folder 14)
    - Survey design and method, undated (Box 100, Folder 15-17)
  - Subseries 5: State and Local Politics
    - Barnes, Michael, Maryland campaign, 1983 (Box 101, Folder 1)
    - Black mayors, 1970s (Box 101, Folder 2-5)
    - California, 1920s-1930s (Box 101, Folder 6-9)
    - Chicago, 1920s-1930s (Box 101, Folder 10-11)
    - Chicago, 1920s-1930s (Box 102, Folder 1-6)
    - City politics, 1931 (Box 102, Folder 7)
    - Citizens' councils, 1930s-1940s (Box 102, Folder 8)
    - Cleveland, 1930 (Box 102, Folder 9)
    - Detroit, 1938 (Box 102, Folder 10)
    - Georgia, 1933 (Box 102, Folder 11)
    - "Hoover Study on Election Trends," circa 1931 (Box 102, Folder 12-13)
    - Illinois, 1930s (Box 102, Folder 14)
    - Illinois, 1930s (Box 103, Folder 1-6)
    - Iowa, 1950 (Box 103, Folder 7)
    - Kansas, 1936-1938 (Box 103, Folder 8-9)
    - Louisiana, 1930 (Box 103, Folder 10)
    - Maryland, Sixth District, undated (Box 103, Folder 11)
    - Minnesota, 1929 (Box 103, Folder 12)
    - Missouri, 1938 (Box 103, Folder 13)
    - Montgomery County, Maryland, 1950s-1970s (Box 103, Folder 14-16)
    - Montgomery County, Maryland, 1950s-1970s (Box 104, Folder 1-2)
    - New York, 1930s-1940s (Box 104, Folder 3)
    - Philadelphia, 1938 (Box 104, Folder 4)
    - Rochester, 1931-1932 (Box 104, Folder 5)
    - "Role of a Governor," circa 1960 (Box 104, Folder 6)
    - St. Louis, 1941 (Box 104, Folder 7)
    - State finances, undated (Box 104, Folder 8)
    - State parties, 1960s (Box 104, Folder 9)
    - State primaries, undated (Box 104, Folder 10)
    - State returns, 1920s-1930s (Box 104, Folder 11)
    - Suffrage, American (Box 104, Folder 12)
    - Suffrage, states (Box 104, Folder 13-17)
    - Suffrage, women, circa 1930s (Box 104, Folder 18)
    - Temperance leagues, 1960s (Box 104, Folder 19)
    - Tennessee, 1939 (Box 105, Folder 1)
    - Texas, 1933 (Box 105, Folder 2)
    - Virginia, 1960s (Box 105, Folder 3-5)
    - Washington, DC, circa 1960s (Box 105, Folder 6-11)
  - Subseries 6: World Politics
    - Arms trade, undated (Box 105, Folder 12)
    - Anglo-American relations, 1940-1941 (Box 105, Folder 13-14)
    - Australia and South Africa, circa 1950s (Box 105, Folder 15)
    - Austria, undated (Box 105, Folder 16)
    - Belgium, 1954, undated (Box 105, Folder 17-18)
    - Britain, 1920s, undated (Box 106, Folder 1-11)
    - Britain, 1920s-1940s, undated (Box 107, Folder 1-11)
    - Britain, undated (Box 108, Folder 1)
    - Canada, 1930s-1950s (Box 108, Folder 2)
    - China, 1950s (Box 108, Folder 3)
    - Cold War, undated (Box 108, Folder 4)
    - Developing countries, 1955-1956 (Box 108, Folder 5)
    - European elections, 1934, undated (Box 108, Folder 6-7)
    - France, 1936 (Box 108, Folder 8-12)
    - Germany, 1930s-1950s (Box 108, Folder 13-14)
    - Germany, 1930s-1950s (Box 109, Folder 1-6)
    - Greece, 1956 (Box 109, Folder 7)
    - Indonesia, 1950s (Box 109, Folder 8-10)
    - Italy, undated (Box 109, Folder 11)
    - Italy, undated (Box 110, Folder 1-2)
    - Japan, 1940 (Box 110, Folder 3-4)
    - Korea, 1950-1951 (Box 110, Folder 5-6)
    - League of Nations, 1920-1925 (Box 110, Folder 7)
    - Middle East, 1954-1967 (Box 110, Folder 8-10)
    - National stereotypes, 1946-1961 (Box 110, Folder 11)
    - "Parliamentary Suffrage," 1932 (Box 110, Folder 12)
    - Philippines, 1946-1953 (Box 110, Folder 13-15)
    - Philippines, 1946-1953 (Box 111, Folder 1-5)
    - Socialist parties, circa 1930s-1950s (Box 111, Folder 6)
    - South America, undated (Box 111, Folder 7)
    - Soviet Union, 1960s (Box 111, Folder 8-14)
    - Soviet Union, 1960s (Box 112, Folder 1-7)
    - Sudan, undated (Box 112, Folder 8)
    - Sweden, 1948 (Box 112, Folder 9)
    - Switzerland, 1936 (Box 112, Folder 10)
    - Thailand, 1962 (Box 112, Folder 11)
    - United Nations, 1945 (Box 112, Folder 12)
    - Vietnam, circa 1950s-1970s (Box 113, Folder 1-4)
    - "Who Pays for War?" undated (Box 113, Folder 5)
    - "The World Strength of Communist Party Organizations," 1956 (Box 113, Folder 6-7)
    - World War II, 1930s-1940s (Box 113, Folder 8-11)
  - Subseries 7: General
    - Academic Freedom (Box 113, Folder 12)
    - American Federation of Labor (Box 113, Folder 13)
    - American parties and elections (Box 113, Folder 14-16)
    - Anti-intellectualism (Box 114, Folder 1)
    - Apportionments (Box 114, Folder 2)
    - Ballots (Box 114, Folder 3)
    - Barber, James David, speech (Box 114, Folder 4)
    - Bibliographies (Box 114, Folder 5-13)
    - "Books to order" (Box 114, Folder 14)
    - Broadcasting (Box 114, Folder 15)
    - Brownlow, Louis, conversation (Box 114, Folder 16)
    - "Bulletins from Britain" (Box 114, Folder 17)
    - "Bulletin of the Orton Society" (Box 114, Folder 18)
    - "Careers of Selected National Chairmen" (Box 114, Folder 19)
    - Case studies in practical politics and parties (Box 114, Folder 20-22)
    - CIA (Box 114, Folder 23)
    - Bibliography files (Box 115)
    - Citizen participation, Fifth National Conference on Citizenship, 1950 Folder 3: Citizenship Clearing House (Box 116, Folder 1-2)
    - City government (Box 116, Folder 4)
    - Civic education (Box 116, Folder 5)
    - Clippings (Box 116, Folder 6-7)
    - Clippings (Box 117, Folder 1-10)
    - Code of ethics for human experimentation (Box 118, Folder 1)
    - Cold War (Box 118, Folder 2)
    - Commissions of inquiry (Box 118, Folder 3)
    - Communications theory (Box 118, Folder 4)
    - Communist parties (Box 118, Folder 5)
    - Comparative government (Box 118, Folder 6)
    - Comparative party theories (Box 118, Folder 7)
    - Comparative study of communication systems (Box 118, Folder 8)
    - Conflict and consensus (Box 118, Folder 9)
    - Congressman Taber, conversation (Box 118, Folder 10)
    - Consensus (Box 118, Folder 11)
    - Consent and conformity (Box 118, Folder 12)
    - Conservative politics (Box 118, Folder 13)
    - Constitutionalism (Box 118, Folder 14)
    - "Contact" (Box 118, Folder 15)
    - Content analysis (Box 118, Folder 16-17)
    - Cooper, Joseph D. (Box 118, Folder 18-19)
    - Courts (Box 118, Folder 20)
    - Defense preparation (Box 118, Folder 21)
    - Democracy (Box 118, Folder 22-24)
    - Democracy (Box 119, Folder 1)
    - Democratic ideology (Box 119, Folder 2)
    - DeGrazia, Alfred (Box 119, Folder 3)
    - Diet (Box 119, Folder 4)
    - Dodd, Stuart Carter, "A Dimensional system of Human Values" (Box 119, Folder 5)
    - Election graphs and bibliographies (Box 119, Folder 6)
    - "The Election Process," lecture (Box 119, Folder 7)
    - Ewing, Russell, leadership (Box 119, Folder 8)
    - Ewing, Russell, syllabus on political parties (Box 119, Folder 9)
    - Exogenous representation (Box 119, Folder 10)
    - Fascists in the United States (Box 119, Folder 11)
    - Federal initiative process (Box 119, Folder 12)
    - "First Monday" magazine (Box 119, Folder 13)
    - Force, political violence (Box 119, Folder 14)
    - Foreign languages (Box 119, Folder 15)
    - Foreign notes (Box 119, Folder 16)
    - "Fortune" (Box 119, Folder 17-18)
    - Functions of state (Box 119, Folder 19)
    - Goods (Box 119, Folder 20)
    - Harding, Warren G. (Box 119, Folder 21)
    - Harter, propaganda (Box 119, Folder 22)
    - "History of the Zenoviev Letter" (Box 119, Folder 23)
    - Hoover, Herbert (Box 119, Folder 24)
    - Folder House Select Committee on Lobbying Activities (Box 120, Folder 1)
    - Humour (Box 120, Folder 2)
    - "Ike: A Record of Courage" (Box 120, Folder 3)
    - Immigration literary test (Box 120, Folder 4)
    - Integration, independent schools (Box 120, Folder 5)
    - Intensity (Box 120, Folder 6)
    - "Invitation from National Geographic" (Box 120, Folder 7)
    - "Is Democracy Failing?" (Box 120, Folder 8)
    - Issue orientation (Box 120, Folder 9-10)
    - Jefferson, Thomas (Box 120, Folder 11)
    - Johnson Charles Albert, "Development of the Presidential Personalities of the Campaign of 1828" (Box 120, Folder 12)
    - Johnson, Lyndon B. (Box 120, Folder 13)
    - Judicial process (Box 120, Folder 14)
    - Katz, changing attitudes (Box 120, Folder 15)
    - Key, V.O. (Box 120, Folder 16)
    - "Keysort Manual" (Box 120, Folder 17)
    - Kircheimer, Otto (Box 120, Folder 18)
    - "Knowledge and Opinion in American Foreign Policy" (Box 120, Folder 19)
    - Labor parties (Box 121, Folder 1)
    - Landesco, John, The Illinois Crime Survey, outline (Box 121, Folder 2)
    - Lasswell, intelligence and policy (Box 121, Folder 3)
    - "Laws and Regulations for Purchase and Lease of State Lands" (Box 121, Folder 4)
    - Leadership (Box 121, Folder 5-7)
    - Legislative records (Box 121, Folder 8)
    - "The Liberal Agent" (Box 121, Folder 9)
    - Liberal parties (Box 121, Folder 10)
    - Library of Congress, letter of deposit (Box 121, Folder 11)
    - Lincoln, Abraham (Box 121, Folder 12)
    - Lincoln University, "The College and the Negro's Struggle for Citizenship," lecture (Box 121, Folder 13)
    - Linkage (Box 121, Folder 14)
    - "Literary Digest" (Box 121, Folder 15-18)
    - Machine politics (Box 121, Folder 19)
    - Makingie, "Community Forces: A Study of Non-Partisan Municipal Elections In Seattle" (Box 121, Folder 20)
    - Majority rule (Box 121, Folder 21)
    - Maps and graphs (Box 122, Folder 1-3)
    - Marist College (Box 122, Folder 4)
    - McLuhan, Marshall (Box 122, Folder 5)
    - Media (Box 122, Folder 6)
    - Merriam, Charles E. (Box 122, Folder 7)
    - Minor parties (Box 122, Folder 8)
    - Morale (Box 122, Folder 9)
    - Mussolini (Box 123, Folder 1)
    - National Citizens Movement for Free Elections (Box 123, Folder 2-3)
    - National roots theory (Box 123, Folder 4)
    - NATO Third Anniversary (Box 123, Folder 5)
    - Naturalization and citizenship (Box 123, Folder 6)
    - Neglected franchise (Box 123, Folder 7)
    - Negro politics and population (Box 123, Folder 8-14)
    - Nixon, Richard (Box 123, Folder 15)
    - Nixon, Richard (Box 124, Folder 1)
    - Notes (Box 124, Folder 2-6)
    - One-party dictatorships (Box 124, Folder 7)
    - Opinion form (Box 124, Folder 8)
    - "Opportunity: The Journal of Negro Life" (Box 124, Folder 9)
    - Organized institutional control (Box 124, Folder 10)
    - "The Origins of Political Behaviorism" (Box 124, Folder 11)
    - Park, R.E. (Box 124, Folder 12)
    - Party discipline (Box 124, Folder 13)
    - Party leaders (Box 124, Folder 14)
    - Party theory (Box 124, Folder 15-16)
    - Personnel administration (Box 124, Folder 17)
    - Policy agencies (Box 124, Folder 18)
    - Political symbols and propaganda (Box 125, Folder 1)
    - Political theory (Box 125, Folder 2)
    - "Politics and numbers" (Box 125, Folder 3)
    - Polls (Box 125, Folder 4)
    - Popular conceptions of bureaucracy (Box 125, Folder 5)
    - Popular law (Box 125, Folder 6-7)
    - Popular law making charts (Box 125, Folder 8)
    - Population (Box 125, Folder 9)
    - "Portrait of Americans in Wartime" (Box 125, Folder 10)
    - Power politics (Box 125, Folder 11)
    - Preferential ballots (Box 125, Folder 12)
    - Presidency (Box 125, Folder 13-14)
    - Press relations (Box 125, Folder 15)
    - Pressure gap (Box 125, Folder 16)
    - Pressure groups (Box 126, Folder 1-2)
    - "Problems Getting Scholarly Works Published" (Box 126, Folder 3)
    - Proportional representation (Box 126, Folder 4-7)
    - "Proposal for a committee on national political parties and elections" (Box 126, Folder 8)
    - Psychological war (Box 126, Folder 9)
    - Psychology (Box 126, Folder 10)
    - Public administration (Box 126, Folder 11-13)
    - Public law (Box 126, Folder 14)
    - Public records law (Box 127, Folder 1)
    - Publishers (Box 127, Folder 2)
    - "Quadrennial County Complexions" (Box 127, Folder 3)
    - Qualities of leadership (Box 127, Folder 4)
    - Race relations (Box 127, Folder 5-9)
    - Referenda (Box 127, Folder 10)
    - "Report of the Committee on Pressure Groups and Propaganda" (Box 127, Folder 11)
    - Representation (Box 127, Folder 12)
    - Representation (Box 128, Folder 1)
    - Reprint list (Box 128, Folder 2)
    - Research plans (Box 128, Folder 3)
    - Roosevelt, Franklin D. (Box 128, Folder 4-6)
    - Roosevelt, Theodore (Box 128, Folder 7)
    - Rumor (Box 128, Folder 8)
    - Scaling (Box 128, Folder 9)
    - Schuman, political power (Box 128, Folder 10)
    - Select committees (Box 128, Folder 11-13)
    - Service state (Box 128, Folder 14)
    - Shortwave radio (Box 129, Folder 1)
    - Skill hierarchies (Box 129, Folder 2)
    - Smith, T.V., retirement (Box 129, Folder 3)
    - Socialist propaganda (Box 129, Folder 4)
    - Sociology, prisons (Box 129, Folder 5)
    - Speeches by others (Box 129, Folder 6-7)
    - "State of the Union," 1971, 1972 (Box 129, Folder 8-9)
    - Steffens, Lincoln (Box 129, Folder 10)
    - "Straight from the Shoulder: A Journal of Political Fact" (Box 129, Folder 11)
    - Suffrage (Box 129, Folder 12-13)
    - Symbols and propaganda (Box 129, Folder 14)
    - Taxation (Box 129, Folder 15)
    - Trends in government (Box 129, Folder 16)
    - Truman (Box 129, Folder 17-18)
    - Unidentified (Box 129, Folder 19-20)
    - Unidentified (Box 130, Folder 1-7)
    - United States federal judiciary (Box 130, Folder 8)
    - United States government publications (Box 130, Folder 9)
    - Vegetarianism and animal rights (Box 130, Folder 10)
    - "Vista," magazine (Box 130, Folder 11)
    - Voting (Box 130, Folder 12)
    - Watergate (Box 131, Folder 1)
    - Welfare (Box 131, Folder 2)
    - "Women Use the Vote" (Box 131, Folder 3)
    - Wooley, Robert, conversation (Box 131, Folder 4)
    - Words (Box 131, Folder 5)
    - Yankee Magazine (Box 131, Folder 6)
- Series VIII: Oversized
  This series contains books, clippings, graphs, electoral maps, and campaigns posters, primarily related to American and British elections. Material has been transferred from Series III and VII. It spans 1922-1940.
  - Calendar, Howard University, 1967-1968 (Box 132)
  - Campaign posters and maps, Philippines, circa 1953 (Box 132)
  - Campaign posters, presidential election, 1924 (Box 132)
  - Campaign posters, Thomas Dewey, 1944 (Box 132)
  - Campaign poster, Robert M. Lafollette, undated (Box 132)
  - Census form, Virginia, undated (Box 132)
  - Chart, federal government, undated (Box 132)
  - Clippings, Britain, 1929 (Box 132)
  - Electoral graphs and maps, Britain, 1922-1929 (Box 132)
  - Electoral instructions, Britain, circa 1924 (Box 132)
  - Electoral map, France, undated (Box 132)
  - Electoral maps, Philippines, circa 1953 (Box 132)
  - Electoral maps, United States, 1910, 1950-1952 (Box 132)
  - Electoral map, Washington DC, 1963 (Box 132)
  - Graph, presidential election, 1964 (Box 132)
  - Maps, Indonesia, undated (Box 132)
  - Poster, Charles E. Merriam's students, undated (Box 132)
  - "The Republican," 1970 (Box 132)
  - Electoral maps, Britain, 1922 (Box 133)
  - Magazines, "Negroes and the War," "Victory," circa 1940s (Box 133)
  - Truman, Harry, Photo and portraits (Box 133)
  - Report, "The Formation of Public Opinion in World Politics," 1933 (Box 133)
  - Thomas C. Platt, Political Manager, dissertation, Gosnell, 1922 (Box 134)
  - Grey Towers: A Campus Novel, 1923 (Box 135)
  - International Directory of Opinion and Attitude Research, 1948 (Box 135)
  - Selected Readings in the Study of Contemporary Society, 1940 (Box 135)
- Series IX: Restricted
  This series contains graded student work and letters of recommendation. These date from Gosnell's employment at the University of Chicago (1926-1941), American University (1946-1962), and Howard University (1962-1970). Material has been transferred from Series III.
  - Letters of recommendation (Box 136, Folder 1-5)
  - Student grades (Box 136, Folder 6-31)
  - Student grades (Box 137, Folder 1-20)
  - Student grades (Box 138, Folder 1-21)
  - Student grades (Box 139, Folder 1-6)
  - Student work (Box 139, Folder 7-14)
  - Student work (Box 140, Folder 1-12)